# Cameron Chen

#### cameron.ph.chen@amail.com | cameronphchen.aithub.io

Cameron is a tech lead manager and staff software engineer at Google Research and Google Health with a strong passion for research innovation and delivering materialized impact. Cameron is an experienced leader in building cross-functional teams to deliver results ranging from initial proofs-of-concept to productionization. His primary research interests lie at the intersection of machine learning, medicine, and science. His research has been published in leading scientific, clinical, and machine learning venues, including Nature, JAMA, and NeurIPS, and covered by media outlets such as the New York Times, Forbes, and Engadget. Before Google, Cameron worked in ML for algorithmic high-frequency trading, energy, demand forecasting, and neuroscience. He received his PhD in Electrical Engineering and Neuroscience from Princeton University and his BS in Electrical Engineering from National Taiwan University. Cameron was also a recipient of the Google PhD Fellowship.

### Experiences

Tech Lead Manager, Staff Software Engineer, Google Research & Google Health

Palo Alto, CA

2017-

- 2020- Tech Lead Manager, Staff Software Engineer
- 2019-2020 Tech Lead, Senior Software Engineer
- 2017-2019 Software Engineer
- We develop state-of-the-art healthcare Al systems and productionize the systems with an aim to achieve a positive real-world impact.

Quantitative Research Intern, Vatic Labs

New York, NY

• Algorithmic high-frequency trading

Machine Learning Intern, Palantir

Palo Alto, CA

2015 • Energy usage pattern analysis

Machine Learning Scientist Intern, Amazon

Seattle, WA

2014 • Demand forecasting

Intern, McKinsey & Company

Taipei, Taiwan

• Tech product design analysis

### Education

PhD, Princeton University

Princeton, NJ

2012-2017 • Machine

Machine Learning and Computational Neuroscience

BS, National Taiwan University

Taipei, Taiwan

2007-2011 • Electrical Engineering

#### **Selected Publications**

For a full publication list, see <a href="https://scholar.google.com/citations?hl=en&user=OrhZiAlAAAAJ">https://scholar.google.com/citations?hl=en&user=OrhZiAlAAAAJ</a>

- 1. **Chen\***, Liu\*, and Peng, How to develop machine learning models for healthcare. Nature Materials, 2019
- 2. Liu\*, **Chen\***, Krause, and Peng, How to read articles that use machine learning: users' guides to the medical literature. JAMA, 2019.
- 3. Gamble, Jaroensri, ..., and **Chen**, Determining breast cancer biomarker status and associated morphological features using deep learning. Nature Communications Medicine, 2021.
- 4. Lai, Kingslake, Wearing, **Chen** et al. Vulnerability of Antarctica's ice shelves to meltwater-driven fracture. Nature. 2020

## **Selected Awards & Honors**

2016 • Google PhD Fellowship

NeurIPS Oral Presentation (1 of 15 papers accepted for oral presentation)